(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marko.
- And I'm Erica.
- Today we're bringing
you a lesson about the office.
So something related to business, right?
- That's right.
And in this lesson, we're
learning language you
can use to tell someone
they did a good job.
- Okay, so a job well done.
You want to praise somebody.
- That's right.
So we're gonna listen in as a manager
or praise his employee on a presentation.
- Okay, so before we
listen to the dialogue,
let's take a look very
quickly at vocabulary preview.
- Very vocabulary preview.
Well, we're gonna hear
both of these words
in the dialogue and
the first one is a whiz.
- Whiz.
- To be a whiz.
- Okay, so it's an adjective
somebody is a whiz.
- That's right.
And whiz comes from the word wizard.
- Okay, so kind of like
a witch, but a guy witch.
- Yeah, man, witch.
But so a whiz is someone
who is really good at something.
- Okay, so I can say
David is a computer whiz.
- Or Antony is a math whiz.
- Okay, so he's really
good at computers or he's
really good at math or
he knows a lot about math.
- Exactly.
- Okay, and our second word.
- Well, we're gonna hear about slides.
- Slides. - Powerpoint slides.
- Powerpoint slides, okay.
So everyone knows PowerPoint, right?
- A computer program.
- A computer program that
you use to make presentations.
- And a slide is one
page in that presentation.
- Okay, so if you have 10
pages in your PowerPoint
presentation, you
basically have 10 slides.
- Exactly.
- Very good.
So now let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time
and we're gonna see what's
happening in this business meeting.
- And so that concludes my outline
for our marketing strategy next year.
Thank you very much for your time.
- Hey, that was quite the presentation.
Honestly, I was completely blown
away by your strategy outline.
I've got to say Alex,
you really wild me today.
- Man, come on, it was nothing.
I'm just doing my job.
- No, I think you deserve
some recognition here.
I mean, if I look back on your previous
presentations, this is a huge improvement.
- Well, Kristen did give
me a head of the slides.
She's a real whiz on PowerPoint.
- And I saw that you took on board
my feedback about pricing strategies.
I really appreciate you taking the
time to think through my suggestions.
- Yeah, well, that was some good advice.
You made some really good points.
- Well, I just wanted to say, well done.
Really, you did a great job.
- All right, well, it sounds
like the employee is a little
bit shy or embarrassed by
receiving all of these compliments.
- Yeah, I guess he's kind
of being humble about it.
- Exactly.
So why don't we move
on to the language now?
There are so many really
useful phrases in this dialogue
that I think we're just
gonna focus on those today.
So let's get started with Fluency Builder.
- Fluency Builder.
- Okay, so today on Fluency
Builder, let's start with our first phrase.
The boss was so impressed
with the presentation
that he said, "I was
completely blown away.
" - To be completely blown away.
- Okay, so to be completely blown away.
- Or to be blown away.
- All right, so what does
that mean to be blown away?
- To be surprised and amazed,
but in a very positive way.
- Okay, so I can say, I'm surprised I'm
amazed, but I'm still not very clear on this.
Why don't we listen to a couple of
examples of how we could use this phrase?
- Example one.
Karl blew me away with his
knowledge of political science.
- Example two.
- I was blown away when I heard
that Jenny and Rick had gotten married.
They had known each
other for less than a month.
Example three.
- My parents were blown away
when they found out I had a tattoo.
- Okay, so I think that's
a little bit clearer now.
And this is a wonderful
way to give your praise
to someone when they do
something really amazing.
- Okay, so completely blown away.
You blew me away.
- That's right.
Now, what about our second word?
- Well, it's quite similar.
The boss said that you really wowed me.
- You wowed me to wow someone.
- Okay, so it spelled W-O-O-Wow.
- So when you wow someone,
you make that person go wow.
- Okay, so you impress
somebody to wow someone.
I can use it as a verb, wow to me.
I wanna wow you.
- Well, I want you to wow me.
- Okay, so wow.
Now, let's take a look at our third phrase.
The guy, he's a little bit shy.
He's trying to be a little bit humble
about receiving so many compliments.
So he says, oh, it was nothing.
- It was nothing.
- Really, it was nothing.
- So that's the way of saying it
wasn't hard or it's not a big deal.
- It's not that important.
- Exactly.
So if somebody's saying wow, thank
you so much for lending me your car.
- It was nothing.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- It's a polite way actually to
respond to a nice compliment.
- Very good.
So before we move on to our next phrase,
let's listen to a couple of
examples with it was nothing.
Example one.
- Thanks for lending me your car this week.
I really appreciate it.
- It's okay, really.
It was nothing.
Example two.
- I can't believe you organized
the surprise birthday party.
Thank you so much.
- Don't worry about it.
It was nothing.
- Okay, so I think that's pretty clear.
Now our final phrase
here for fluency builder,
the employee said that
Kirsten gave him a hand.
Okay, so to give someone
a hand, give me a hand.
- Give me a hand.
Basically to help someone
help me or assist me.
Okay, so to help someone to give
me a hand or let me give you a hand.
- That's right.
- All right, very good.
So great phrases and fluency builder today.
I think it's time for us to listen to
the dialogue for the second time.
We're gonna slow it
down a little bit so we can
catch all these phrases
and then we'll come back.
(upbeat music)
- And so that concludes my outline
for our marketing strategy for next year.
Thank you very much for your time.
- Hey, that was quite the presentation.
Honestly, I was completely blown
away by your strategy outline.
I've gotta say, Alex,
you really wild me today.
- Ah, come on, it was nothing.
I'm just doing my job.
- No, I think you deserve
some recognition here.
I mean, if I look back on your previous
presentations, this is a huge improvement.
- Well, Kristen did give
me a hand with the slides.
She's a real whiz on PowerPoint.
- And I saw that you took on board
my feedback about pricing strategies.
I really appreciate you taking the time
to think through my suggestions.
- Yeah, well, that was some good advice.
You made some really good points.
- Well, I just wanted to say, well done.
Really, you did a great job.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so Michael said before, there's
a lot of really helpful phrases in here
and we're gonna look at a few
more of these in putting it together.
Put them in it together.
Okay, so let's start with the first phrase.
The boss was quite impressed with him and
he said, that was quite the presentation.
- That was quite the presentation.
- All right, quite the presentation.
- So this phrase, quite the presentation.
It means it was good, right?
It was special.
- It was very good.
- Yep, now we can take the noun presentation
out and replace it with any other noun.
All right, so I can say, Bob
is quite the basketball player.
Why don't we listen now
for a few more examples?
Example one.
- I heard you are quite the dancer.
Can you teach me some moves?
- Example two.
- Carl is quite the ladies' man.
He is very good when it
comes to talking to girls.
- Example three.
Nancy is quite gifted at math.
She can solve any math
problem you give her.
- So you're saying in a very good
way that something is very good.
- Or special.
- Very special. - Very special.
- All right, so the boss was very
impressed with the employee and he said,
and I saw that you took
on board my feedback.
- To take on board my feedback.
- Okay, so take on board something.
So here my feedback
is my suggestions, right?
And when you take on board my feedback
you accept my feedback and you use it.
- Okay, so I can say, for example, I
want you to take on board my ideas.
- Or Jenny took on board
a few of my suggestions.
I was really happy.
- Okay, very good.
So to take on board, to accept and use.
- All right, so take on board feedback,
take on board suggestion,
take on board ideas.
- Okay, very good.
And we have one more phrase on putting it
together today to think something through.
- To think it through.
- Okay, so think it through.
- So here the boss said that he took
the time to think through my suggestions.
So think through, what does that mean?
- To think carefully about
all of the details of something.
- Okay, so to take into
consideration all the aspects.
- Right, so why don't we give an example?
If you're thinking through a plan, right?
You don't just think about
the end, the outcome.
You wanna think about all of the
small details, the steps in that plan.
- Okay, so maybe I wanna buy a new car,
but it's a lot of money, so I
really have to think it through.
- So you have to think
carefully about everything
that is involved in
buying the new car.
All the money you're gonna
have to not spend on parties
and exactly you have to think it through,
you have to analyze it very carefully.
- That's right, so let's give a few
examples of how we can use this phrase.
Hey Marco, have you thought
through my suggestions?
- I can say you guys
are very young, I think.
You should think it through
before you get married.
- Good advice.
- Okay, so to think it through.
- Okay, so three great phrases
and why don't we hear them
one more time in our dialogue?
(upbeat music)
And so that concludes my outline
for our marketing strategy next year.
Thank you very much for your time.
- Hey, that was quite the presentation.
Honestly, I was completely blown
away by your strategy outline.
I've gotta say Alex,
you really wild me today.
- Man, come on, it was nothing.
I'm just doing my job.
- No, I think you deserve
some recognition here.
I mean, if I look back on your previous
presentations, this is a huge improvement.
- Well, Kristen did give
me a head of the slides.
She's a real whiz on PowerPoint.
- And I saw that you took on board
my feedback about pricing strategies.
I really appreciate you taking the
time to think through my suggestions.
- Yeah, well, that was some good advice.
You made some really good points.
- Well, I just wanted to say, well done.
Really, you did a great job.
(upbeat music)
Okay, great dialogue and some interesting
phrases for giving praise, right?
That's, I think, very
important in the workplace.
- Yeah, and you know what, I read recently
that something like six
out of every 10 employees
don't get regular
praise from their boss.
- Yeah, it's very important.
And in some cultures,
well, it's not very common
to praise or to give positive
feedback to their employees.
- Yeah, but I think for Western employees,
actually it's really important
and it helps them work harder.
The more times they hear job well done.
- Yeah, very good.
So now you have the
tools that maybe you can
use with your employees
or with your friends.
- With your friends.
- Yep.
- Okay, so if you have any
questions, comments, or
doubts, please come to
our website, EnglishPod.com.
- Yep, Marco and I are
always around to help you out.
So until next time, thanks
for listening and goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)